Luca Santarella

C. 973-413-7724

Essex Fells, NJ 07021

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the healthcare and medical device industries. Skilled in engineering and executing full stack applications (backend, web, and mobile). Powerful R&D Lead that always propels technology forward to increase performance and grow business.

Skills

- R&D leadership
- HL7 Integrations
- Kubernetes & Docker
- Istio Service Mesh
- AWS
- GRPC
- REST APIs
- Golang
- PHP
- C & C++
- MySQL
- MongoDB / DocumentDB
- React
- JQuery
- HTML5 & CSS3
- Unit Testing
- CI / CD (Travis, CircleCI)

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science

New Jersey Institute of Technology Computer Science

• 4.0 GPA

Experience

DocSpera, Inc

R&D Lead - Full Stack Software Developer | Sunnyvale, CA 01/2017 to Current

- Developed integration tools for connecting EMRs with DocSpera backend.
- Designed and lead the transition to container based infrastructure to improve performance and scalability.
- Introduced services meshes and gRPC to the technology stack.
- Developed a full stack mobile application to track patient progress through the episode of care.
- Pioneered quality assurance processes, including unit testing and documentation of tests.
- Implemented full service backend framework in PHP / MySQL / Solr with API exposition in REST/JSON.

Orthotrax

Founder, CEO | Morristown, NJ 01/2018 to Current

- Developed Medical Device Logistics software for small manufacturers and independent ASC customers.
- Signed two long term customers within the first year of business.
- End to end execution, from idea to product execution.

Healthstock, Inc.

Full Stack Software Developer | Sunnyvale, CA 01/2017 to 01/2018

- Demonstrated HIPAA compliance in handling all patient health information
- Implemented a secure backend service with security measures to ensure patient and physician health information remains secure and uncompromised.
- Developed lighting fast single page frontend application with client side caching to ensure excellent mobile and desktop performance.

High School Diploma

Oratory Preparatory School

- Ranked in Top 10% of class
- Inducted into the Cum Laude Society, an international society dedicated to honoring scholastic achievement in secondary schools

AgShift, Inc

Backend Developer | San Jose, CA 03/2017 to 07/2017

- Worked closely with business partners to create and deliver high-value solutions to meet their needs.
- Blended machine learning with computer vision to enable a fully transparent and digitized food selection and distribution system.
- Developed the frontend and backend architecture to utilize observational data to enhance machine learning algorithms.

Corentec America, Inc

Software Developer | Morristown, NJ 09/2015 to 08/2016

- Architected a medical device "Rep-Less" business model.
- Planned, developed, and executed the creation of of a medical device logistics system, implementing both inventory management and accounting principles.
- Conducted outreach programs by meeting with surgeons and healthcare staff to gain user input and translate customer feedback into tangible product results.

Corentec America, Inc

IT Systems Administrator | Morristown, NJ 03/2015 to 09/2015

- Provisioned Exchange and Active Directory server systems for internal company communications.
- Managed and maintained company infrastructure and provided on-site technical support.

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://lucasantarella.com
- https://linkedin.com/in/lucasantarella/